Guide to the Gregory Corso Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Gregory Corso Papers
1949-1996.
Corso, Gregory.
5 linear ft ( 10 document boxes and 7 oversized folders)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library New York, NY. 10027
MS#0285
4078654
Includes published and unpublished writings, artwork, correspondence, and sound recordings created by or related to the Beat poet Gregory Corso.
Biographical Note
Gregory Nunzio Corso, born to very young Italian immigrants in New York's Greenwich Village, had a troubled childhood. His mother left Corso's father and her son within a year of Gregory's birth, and he spent most of his youth moving between different foster homes and orphanages or living on the street. As a teenager, he landed briefly in jail and spent three months under psychiatric evaluation at Bellevue, but it was his three years incarcerated in New York's Clinton State Prison (as a repeat offender for theft) that proved to be transformative for Corso. In the prison library he discovered Rimbaud and Percy Shelley and it was during this stint in jail that he began to write poetry.
In 1950, upon his release from prison, Corso again began to frequent the bars and cafés of Greenwich Village. It was here that he met Allen Ginsberg who introduced the young poet to Jack Kerouac, William S. Burroughs, Neal Cassady, and the rest of the original members of the Beat Generation. Corso's commitment to creating spontaneous poetry fit in well with the beats' "New Vision" for American poetry and Corso was quickly integrated into the group of friends, traveling with them to give poetry readings in San Francisco and collaborating with them on various creative projects.
Corso's first book of poetry, The Vestal Lady on Brattle was published in 1955 and gained Corso some critical acclaim and enough money to fund his travels through abroad. He traveled through Europe and set up residence in the Paris boarding house later christened the Beat Hotel and, along with Ginsberg, Orlovsky, and Kerouac, traveled to Tangier to help William Burroughs edit teh amnuscript of The Naked Lunch.
Corso returned to New York in 1958 in time to see his book of poetry, Gasoline, published as part of City Lights' Pocket Poet series. Though he did write some plays and some prose, most notably the novel The American Express, his prime focus was always on his poetry and he published a number of books of poetry throughout his career and lectured on creative writing and poetry.
Gregory Corso died of complications from prostate cancer in 2001. He was 70 years old.
Scope and Content
The Gregory Corso Papers contains correspondence, artwork, and published and unpublished writings, as well as photographs and sound recordings of Corso and fellow beat writers. Many of the items in the collection include explanatory notes or annotations that Corso added when preparing to sell these papers.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in 6 series:
Series I. Correspondence, 1955-1979 and Undated
Series II. Photographs, 1962-1967 and Undated
Series III. Writings, 1949-1996 and Undated
Series IV. Artwork, 1954-1977 and Undated
Series V. Printed Material, 1958-1972 and Undated
Series VI. Sound Recordings, 1966 and Undated
Subjects
Corso, Gregory.; Ferlinghetti, Lawrence.; Ginsberg, Allen, 1926-1997.; Olson, Charles, 1910-1970.; Orlovsky, Peter, 1933-; Soyer, Raphael, 1899-1987.; Biderman, Peggy.; Beat generation.; American literature--20th century.; Bohemianism--United States.; Poets, American--20th century.; Poems.; Drawings.; Galley proofs.; Journals.; Manuscripts.; Notebooks.; Paintings.; Poets, American.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located on-site.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1980 M-80 Purchase (26312E; 28027E; 09853F; 637912; 297-5/9/80)
10/02/89 M-89-10-02 Typescript and galley proofs of MINDFIELDS. Gotham Book Mart 293 (Gen)
Related Material-- At Columbia
Reminiscences of Gregory Nunzio Corso: Oral History, Columbia University Oral History Research Office
Allen Ginsberg Papers, 1943-1991 Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Columbia University.
Related Material-- Other Repositories
Gregory Corso Collection, 1890-1978, Harry Ransom Humanities Research Center, University of Texas.
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1955-1979 and Undated
  This series contains correspondence written to Corso as well as letters and notes written by Corso to others. The material is arranged alphabetically by correspondent's last name, and then chronologically within each correspondent. Letters written by Corso that remain in the collection are generally items that were written but never posted, rather than carbons of outgoing correspondence.
  - Ansen, Allen to Corso, 1969 January (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biderman, Peggy to Jonathan Robbins, 1977 March 14 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Corso, Gregory
    - Unaddressed, July 25 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Unaddressed, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
      (Postscript from letter- notes on Egyptian hieroglyphics)
    - To Peggy Biderman, undated, (4 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 5 to 8)
    - To Lenore Kandel Fritsch, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - To Allen Ginsbery and Peter Orlovsky, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - To Michael Horowitz, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - To James Laughlin, undated, (2 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 12 to 13)
    - To Rosie, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - To Stephen Spender, et.al., undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - To Ted Wilentz, circa 1955 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - To Michael Horowitz, 1959 October 8 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - To Jack Kerouac, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - To William Burroughs, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - To Michael Horowitz, 1963 June 15 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - To Allen Ginsberg, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - To James Laughlin, 1965 October 15 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      (incomplete)
    - Unaddressed, 1965 November 2 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - To Ettore Sottsass and Fernanda Sottsass Pivano, December, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - To Allen Ginsberg and Peter Orlovsky, 1966 June 3 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - To Allen Ginsberg, 1966 August 25 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - To Andreas Brown, 1969, (2 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 27 to 28)
    - To Andreas Brown, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      (sent with "Elegaic Feelings American")
    - To The Government, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - To "Cher Lawyer," 1969 January 23 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - To Peggy Biderman
      - 197- (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - 1974 March 23 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - 1975 May 17 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - 1975 October 9 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - 1975 December 9 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      - 1976 January 19 (Box 1, Folder 37)
      - 1976 March 9 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      - 1976 April (Box 1, Folder 39)
      - 1976 April 16 (Box 1, Folder 40)
        (includes birth announcement for Corso's son Orfeo)
      - 1977 August 8 (Box 1, Folder 42)
      - 1978 (Box 1, Folder 43)
      - 1978 March 10 (Box 1, Folder 44)
      - 1978 October 1 (Box 1, Folder 45)
      - 1979, (2 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 46 to 47)
      - 1979 October 18 (Box 1, Folder 48)
      - 1979 November 9 (Box 1, Folder 49)
      - 1979 December 8 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Unaddressed, 1977 April 4 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Crawford, Cheryl to Corso, 1965 September 9 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Dobell, Byron to Corso, 1965 July 19 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Eberhart, Richard to Corso, 1971 November 2 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence
      - To Corso, 1958 October 13 (Box 1, Folder 54)
      - To Andreas Brown
        - 1969 January 28 (Box 1, Folder 55)
        - 1970 January 27 (Box 1, Folder 56)
        - 1970 February 17 (Box 1, Folder 57)
      - To Corso, 1973 April 14 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Ginsberg Allen, to Corso
      - 1968 October 29 (Box 1, Folder 59)
      - 1969 January 28 (Box 1, Folder 60)
      - 1969 April 15 (Box 1, Folder 61)
      - 1969 June 12 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - 1973 August 15 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - 1974 September 9 (Box 2, Folder 3)
        (with enclosed photographs)
      - 1974 September 13 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Ginsberg Allen, to John Robbins, 1977 February 17 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Laughlin, James to Corso, 1966 March 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Orlovsky, Peter to Gregory Corso, 1965 July 9 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Randall, Margaret and Robert David Cohen to "Dear Friends," 1968 October (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Rogers, Mary to Corso, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Soyer, Raphael to Gregory Corso, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      (written in catalog for Soyer's April 1966 exhibition at the Forum Gallery which included a portrait of Corso)
    - Tortoria, Vincent to Corso, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1965-1969 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Series II: Photographs, 1962-1967 and Undated
  This series contains a small number of photographs, professional portraits as well as snapshopts, of Corso and his friends and associates. There are also a small number of photographs in the correspondence series that were enclosures in letters and remain in their original context; this is noted in the finding aid.
  - Gregory Corso, Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    (signed by Corso)
  - Gregory Corso, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Gregory Corso and Peggy Biderman reading "The Body Electric," 1973 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    (inscribed to Biderman, signed by Corso and Tony Leonardi)
  - Gregory Corso, Peggy Biderman, etc., 1973 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Gregory Corso in New York City, by Elsa Dorfman, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    (signed by Elsa Dorfman and Gregory Corso)
  - Miscellaneous photos of Corso and Associates (including William S. Burroughs and Allen Ginsberg), 1962-1967, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Series III: Writings, 1949-1996 and Undated
  The writings series, the largest in the collection, is primarily comprised of poetry, with some prose writing. The items in this series are listed individually by title, if supplied, or by the first line of the poem. Also included in this series are a number of notebooks containing poems, poetry fragments, notes, and sketches.
  - General Writings and Documents
    - Committee on Poetry's Statement on LeRoi Jones' Trial, 1968 January 6 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Contemporary Poets of the English Language Questionnaire, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Corso's Statement about his Refusal to Sign a Loyalty Oath, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      (with copy of oath)
    - Ginsberg, Allen-- "The Old Man Sings at His White Hair" and Corso-- "Snaked Arms and Bleeding Legs" (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Marcel Proust Questionnaire-- filled out by Corso, 1967 April 9 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Questionnaire for Doubleday & Co., undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Syndicate Plan, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Poems-- by Corso
    - "10 Times a Poem," December, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      (limited edition collection of poetry)
    - "1964 Thoughts on God" (Box 2, Folder 57)
      (multiple drafts)
    - "Academically Speaking" (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - "Agents are cleaning their pistols…" (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - "Ahead… 50 miles ahead…" (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - "All Hallows Eve in Cleveland" (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - "Ah but I feel I know O so and…" (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - "An Eversion of Mischance" (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - 'The Anarchiad" (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - "And as expanded nine billion celled brain…" (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - "And she droned such silences…" (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - "And when 12 belled no one happied…" (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - "The Angel of Old" (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - "Army" (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - "Augments" (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - [Autobiography]
      - Draft Fragments (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - Corrected Proof (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - "Away One Year" (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - "Back to Space" (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - "Battersea Power House" (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - "Between star and quasar wheeling swiftly…" (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - "Between two points I span…" (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - "Birthday Poem," 1973 March 26 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - "Bomb" (Box 2, Folder 49)
      (multiple drafts-- including first draft and multiple variant page layouts)
    - "Burn your convention young child…" (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - "The businessman in all his dignity…" (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - "But I Do Not Need Kindness!" (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - "In Honor of Those the Negroes are Revolting Against" (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - "Church on the Guidecca, Venice" (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - "Circ the circle full- the wooden sun…" (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - "Colleges of the 60's, you are young America…" (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - "Composite 2" (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - "Continental Images" (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - "Crashing down time…" (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - "Dear Villon Dear Milarepa" (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - "December" (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - "Dedication Poem: For Hope, My Angel, My Sura, The Only Girl I Ever Loved" (Box 2, Folder 62)
      (two drafts)
    - "Dialogue" (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - "Dream of Dreams" (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - "Doll Poem" (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - 'Early Morning Poetry" (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - "Ecce Home" (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Ecce Homo "Elegiac Feelings American"
      - "Elegiac Feelings American-- for the Dear Memory of John Kerouac," 1969 (Box 3, Folder 3)
        (original manuscript with corrections)
      - Draft Material not Included in Final Poem, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Drafts-- titled "Gregorian Rants" and "Four" (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Draft titled "Spontaneous Requiem for an American, (2 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 6 to 7)
      - Draft titled "Spontaneous Requiem for a Beautiful American" (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Ramparts Magazine March 1970 (Box 3, Folder 9)
        (contains "Spontaneous Requiem" an early published version of "Elegiac Feelings American")
    - "For Harry's Viva Budgie" (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - "Encounter" (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - "The Eye is Cause of the Sight" (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - "First Impression of Florence" (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - "Flight" (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - "Florida 6" (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - "The Flower Peddler (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - "For K.R. Who Killed Himself in Charles St. Jail," 1957 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      (also includes draft titled "In Memory of K.R.")
    - "For My Pregnant Wife, Be it Girl or Boy" (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - "For the Love of Words- for Wm. Shakespeare's 400th Happy Birthday" (Box 3, Folder 19)
      (multiple drafts including alternate title: For the Poet Who Had a Virgin Language")
    - "Four years I have faced my brow's center…" (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - "Fragment from Novel Prologue-2" and "Fragment from Novel Prologue-3" (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - "From Hell…" (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - "Further Reflections" (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - "The genes of the spirit apparitionate…" (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - "The God I knew to be…" (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - "G.O.P. Convention" (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - "The greatest discovery a man can make…" (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - "Heed me well, embryonic scout…" (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - "Hello…" (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - "High-heeled poverty…" (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - "Hooooooooooo Like a Zoomy Slip of Gold I Go" (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - "How fantastic the soft rocket's lift-off…" (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - "How haunts us the buffaloes earthtight will…" (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - "How so suddenly in a snap like wham…" (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - "How sweetly fast…" (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - "I am a drawn mouse…" (Box 3, Folder 36)
      (with sketch of mouse)
    - "I am no longer I…" (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - "I am not together…" (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - "I am not that I of face…" (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - "I damned both the sword and victim…" (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - "I do not know" (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - "I Held a Shelley Manuscript," 1955 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - "I know all there is to know…" (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - "I long for the time of great Cybele…" (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - "I saw these years of life…" (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - "I sit near my body sleeping…" (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - "I would a tinkler of portents be…" (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - "If a Hollywood star is not my ego…" (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - "If you are earth…" (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - "I'll my marble aeroplane…" (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - "I'll remember earth…" (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - "In a lurid clay vision…" (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - "In Central Park" (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - "In dreams of reality…" (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - "In moving space moves time and change…" (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - "In the middle of the night negroes play…" (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - "In solar camp exiled to a dead star…" (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - "In time there are the elements solitary and undisturbed…" (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - "Infinity meets itself…" (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - "Instead of earth a more difficult planet…" (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - "An instrument of the Muse I am not…" (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - "It is snowing in the summer of my sleep…" (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - "It was hell to come by…" (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - "It wasn't when I lost God I lost life…" (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - "It's getting late…" (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - "It's not like some spy I am…" (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - "The Lammergeyer" (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - "Last Night I Drove a Car…" (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - "Last night was night at its nightest…" (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - "Let Us Inspect the Lyre" (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - "Like a snail leaving its shell…" (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - "Lines Written November 22, 23-1963-- In Discord--" (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - "Lived I in the first house…" (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Long Live Man(multiple drafts of various poems published in Long Live Man) (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - "Lower East Side Puerto Rican Street" (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - "The Mad Yak" (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - "Mafia" (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - "The Making of a Poem- At One Sitting" (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - "Many are the beginnings where legends…" (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - ""Masks and Attainments- for Howard Kanovitz" (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - "Men should wear antlers she said…" (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - "Mind is centered on the cosmosian bar…" (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - "Mind lulling…" (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - "Mine galactic incestry O oaken ma…" (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Mindfield circa 1989
      - Drafts, with manuscript annotations and corrections (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Master Galleys (Box 14-E-6)
        (corrected and annotated)
      - Proofs, (3 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 12 to 14)
    - "The Missing Link is the Birth of Spirit" (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - [Music]-- prose (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - "Mutation of the Spirit: A Shuffle Poem Unshuffled" (Box 14-E-6)
    - "Name Droppings" (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - "Neither white-smocked in science…" (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - "No Doubt What I saw," 1957 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - "No was not the Muse pinned me…" (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - "None Dare Trust Another" (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - "Not often have I hesitated to go beyond…" (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - "Numbers of directions! Lighttime distances!..." (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - "O boats O seas ye nights there…" (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - "O life double me…" (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - "O Mighty Tug" (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - "O my guardian muse…" (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - "O the beauty of all things! The beauty…" (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - "Of Streets and Flowers" (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - "Oh but to be received of wise and sweet…" (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - "The old man of me and…" (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - "On Food" (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - "On Having Once Loved" (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - "On Nearing My 29th Year," 1959 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - "On Poetry" (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - "On the Death of a Chilean Poet," 1957 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - "On the walls of a dull furnished room…" (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - "On a street corner in ancient Cathy…" (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - "1234567890…" (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - "Out of fanciful disorder comes… disorder…" (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - "People are afraid…" (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - "Poem to Michelangelo" (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - "Power" (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Prison Writings-- prose, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - "A prophet walks twice during his tenure…" (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - "A Rambling Poem on a Rambling Trip to Ohio" (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - "Revenge the Hapless Nightmare" (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - "The river runs but the riverbed is steadfast…" (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - "Seated before a banquet of knowledge…" (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - "Setting the Record of Absurdity Straight" (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - "She says flying saucers and is no…" (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - "She of the days of my heart…" (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - "Space is a journey long ago taken…" (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - "The Spell of Wlamtrice Park" (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - "Spooning opiate the lower visibilities…" (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - "Spring's Melodious Herald" (Box 4, Folder 56)
      (early draft entitled "Cythylis")
    - "Still Life" (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - "Suburbia Mad Song" (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Sweet Jesus, swollen on my lips, I speak thy pain…" (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - "The swimming lights in the black are bright pieces of air…" (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - "The Tarot Poems" (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - "Ten thousand million years ago the cosmos was a year old…" (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - "There became so many of us…" (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - "There is nothing missing…" (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - "There is yet time…" (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - 'These truncated troops of palsied geometrics…" (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - "This poem is the mind flow of a damned…" (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - "Thoughts in an Airplane" (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - "Thus when by all great trismegatusian light…" (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - "To be…" (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - "To Bring Back the Dead" (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - "To express a sorrow deep within…" (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - "To hear quasars echo light's first cry…" (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - "To return to my feeling-head…" (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - "The truth about myself…" (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - "Two stars etched on Calabrian stone…" (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - "Unseen journeying in the nuances…" (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - 'The violet-white-blackgreen sky…" (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - [Vision of Rotterdam] (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - "What angel shall sharpen its white on this…" (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - "What I was before I returned the antlers to the stag…" (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - "What separates me from you…" (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - "What to the senses seem…" (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - "What wonderful men…and women…" (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - "When I came upon the mystery's source…" (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - "When I Think to Refrain" (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - "When sweet terror thrills…" (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - "Where by god the time comes to stop…" (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - "Who sees the wind sees…" (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - "Who'll believe what I have seen…" (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - "Who unto themselves are none other…" (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - "Wisdom it was made me so happy…" (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - "With oaken ears…" (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - "Woman Seated in Park" (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - "Written While Watching Lenny Bruce Obscenity Trial" (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - "Yesterday where I live…" (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - "You know my present…" (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - "You too shall be known…" (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Miscellaneous Poems
      - Drafts and Notes- General (Box 5, Folder 38)
      - Notebooks
        - Paris, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 39)
        - Athens, 1966 February-March (Box 5, Folder 40)
        - San Francisco, 1968, (3 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 41 to 4)
        - San Francisco, 1968 February (Box 6, Folder 1)
        - San Francisco, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 2)
        - San Francisco, February, 1969, (2 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 3 to 4)
        - San Francisco, May, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 5)
        - Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 6)